Austin Guest, Programmer

austin.guest@riseup.net | 831.917.6400 | Brooklyn, New York, US https://github.com/aguestuser | https://twitter.com/aguestuser | https://linkedin.com/in/austinguest

SUMMARY

Fast-learning self-taught programmer with deep people skills. Have learned five languages, functional programming, Agile development, and open source management in three years. Looking to work with a tight-knit autonomous team that values intellectual exploration, compassionate communication, and social justice.

EXPERIENCE

where@, Founder, Tech Lead

2015-06-01-2016-05-01

https://whereat.io

- Conceived, architected, wrote prototype, and managed agile team for secure realtime location sharing app
- Wrote majority of code & documentation for multi-tiered secure mobile app, including mobile clients in Java and React Native, web app in React, reactive-streams-based server in Scala
- Led team of eight volunteer developers from ThoughtWorks NYC -- including coaching, pairing, code review, and consensus-building around major architectural decisions
- Received mentorship in threat-modeling, cryptography, and security training from renowned ACLU security technologist Daniel Kahn Gillmore
- Wrote, grouped, and prioritized user stories and epics for four parallel development streams according to Agile best practices
- Developed public-facing ecosystem to optimize paths to access for outside contributors using cutting-edge OSS collaboration platforms (gitter.im, waffle.io, etc.)
- Conducted user tests in simulated and live protests to drive UX and design decisions
- o (Currently) implementing continuous delivery pipeline using good, AWS, and Docker
- o Contributed to gocd's documentation for custom TLS configuration and dockerized tests
- Wrote load tests in Gatling, used results to drive adoption of Kafka-backed distributed server architecture

LittleSis, Software Engineer

2015-03-01-2015-06-01

https://littlesis.org

 Catalyzed migration from monolithic legacy code base to modular, testable design by designing and supervising port of one feature slice from PHP/jQuery to Rails/React

Recurse Center, Autodidact

2014-11-17-2015-02-16

https://recurse.com

- Mastered basic best practices in functional programming in Scala and JavaScript
- Wrote non-blocking chat server in Scala, using futures and a custom wrapper around Java's NIO2 library
- Began work on a Scala BitTorrent client, including custom parser combinators and nonblocking socket IO
- Completed readings and exercises on algorithms, data structures, function composition, monads, concurrency, and recursion

BK Shift, Software Engineer

2014-01-01-2014-11-07

http://bkshift.com

- o Learned full-stack web development, test-driven development, and agile project management
- Learned Ruby and built full-stack Rails app in 3 months
- Reduced time needed to allocate 300-400 weekly shifts to 100-150 riders by over 50%
- Used 1-week Agile sprints to ensure continuous deployment of usable features, front-load completion of learning-rich user stories, provide client with a burn-up chart

- o Deployed and iterated on complex systems approaches to large-scale social change
- Conceived and project-managed Occupy The Boardroom, a web app that sent and displayed personal emails from ordinary people directly to the CEOs of the "Big Six" banks
- Coordinated Occupy Sandy's needs assessment canvass in the Far Rockaways, including design and implementation of distributed data-input system to support to overtaxed on-theground coordinators
- Used NYC's OpenData portal to research property ownership in Crown Heights in support of ongoing affordable housing campaigns; used research to write pamphlets, conduct teach-ins
- Coordinated tactical framework development, trainings and communications infrastructure for mass mobilizations of tens of thousands of people in NYC's financial district

ALIGN (Jobs with Justice NYC), Online Organizer http://alignny.org

2010-06-01-2011-12-01

Managed online strategy for successful citywide campaign to keep Walmart out of New York
City -- growing email list by 38% and generating tens of thousands of YouTube views

SEIU (Service Employees International Union), Organizer https://seiu.org

2009-09-01-2010-03-31

• Contributed to national campaign to organize Sodexo food service workers through on-the-ground committee building and leadership development

EDUCATION

Harvard University

2000-09-01-2007-06-01

BA Performance & Media Studies

o Summa Cum Laude Thesis o High Honors in Major

SKILLS

Languages: Scala, Java, JavaScript/ES6, Ruby, Racket

Paradigms: Functional Programming, Agile Development, Full-stack Web Development, Mobile Development, Network Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Actor-Oriented Programming, Reactive Programming

Libraries/Frameworks: Akka-Streams, Akka-Http, RxJava, React/Redux, React-Native, Rubyon-Rails

Dev Ops: Continuous Delivery, Automated Testing, Go-CD, Concourse, Docker, AWS, Nginx, DigitalOcean, SSL/TLS configuration